Mario Borras

Web Developer

mario.borras@icloud.com 📞 (305) 283-8836 👂 Media, PA 🛚 in marioborras

Summary

Web developer with a strong personal portfolio. Well-versed in the front-end ecosystem and quick to adopt and master new technologies that arise. Previous professional experience in casualty insurance.

Skills

Front-End: HTML, CSS / SASS/LESS, JavaScript ES6 / jQuery, Webpack, iOS Development

Back-End: Node.js, PHP, MYSQL

Project Management & Software Suites: Git (Git Flow), Github, Firebase, Sourcetree/Bitbucket, Mailchimp, Xcode

Frameworks: Vue.js/Vuex, Bootstrap, Framework7, Cordova, React.js **Software & Application:** Microsoft Visual Studio Code, Filezilla

Content Management Systems: Wordpress, Joomla!

Other: Fluency in Spanish

Projects

NERCOMP

HTML5, Sass, JavaScript, WordPress. https://nercomp.org

- Developed a fully responsive website that focused on meeting WCAG 2.1 AA accessibility standards and creating an effective user experience.
- Created a website wizard to launch along with the site, smoothing the transition for users who were accustomed to the previous site.
- Refined filtering UI to be able to filter jobs by location and type

Siegfried MYJourney®

Vue.js, Vuex https://www.siegfriedgroup.com/my-journey/

- Created an inspirational and memorable user experience that communicated MY Journey®'s purpose and goals to engage Siegfried's target audience of outgoing, young professionals
- · Coded site to include multiple audio and visual elements, pushing beyond just a standard website experience.
- Utilized WordPress JSON REST API to make content dynamic and simple to replace and change.

Star Capital Financing iOS App

Vue.js, Cordova, Framework 7, Google Firebase - Star Capital Financing on Apple's App Store

- Developed a feature to allow salesman to produce flyers with pictures taken from device to drive the sale of construction equipment right through the app.
- Enhanced the app's calculator feature to produce unique financing estimates to prospective buyers.
- Launched profile feature to allow users to update information.

Employment

Lyquix · Web Developer · May 2019 to Current · Philadelphia, PA

- Responsible for the development of new client websites and apps, by working through the whole project from discovery, requirements definition, coding
 and testing.
- Maintain and deploy enhancements of existing client websites and apps
- Execute converting design comps into pixel perfect HTML/CSS/Javascript code
- Perform general support to clients and team members
- Monitor performed work and input information in project management systems
- Participate in internal and client meetings or conference calls when needed

State Farm Insurance · Auto Claims Specialist - Complex Property · Aug. 2011 to June 2018 · Concordville, PA

- Responsible for recognizing, investigating, and resolving complex coverage, liability, and damage issues
- · Handled claims involving litigation, complex/non-routine lawsuits, alternative dispute resolution, and extra-contractual damage
- Connected with key stakeholders throughout the claims process, including insured and claimant parties, as well as external vendors

Education

Florida International University · Aug. 2004 to Aug. 2008

B.A. English

New York Code and Design Academy · July 2018 to Oct. 2018

Certificate Full-Stack Web Development Intensive